<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">The Morning Writer</title>
<subtitle type="text">Morning Pages. Every Day.</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2016-05-02T21:59:30-04:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>The Morning Writer</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>info@themorningwriter.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compassion has no limit. Kindness has no enemy.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/compassion-has-no-limit" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/compassion-has-no-limit</id>
  <published>2016-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Morning Writer</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>info@themorningwriter.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feelings are amazing. They have no limits. Such is the case with compassion. We stop thinking about our own problems and issues and start giving towards others. This capacity of humans has no limits, even if we have to stretch beyond our physical limits. We are overcome by a sense of duty and responsibility to help another and get them back to their homeostasis. We don’t like suffering and pain and we can’t tolerate it in others. Especially kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that everyone has the capacity to be compassionate but not everyone does. It is a limitless well of love and understanding but it somehow stays dormant in most people. The problem lies in the way we are being brought up. It is passed down by our parents and society. Environment plays a big part too. We have adopted the idea that we, humans have the power over all living and non-living things on this planet and therefore we must take advantage of it to our best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been taking advantage of our planet for the few last centuries but with greed as our guide and not compassion. Greed has poisoned our souls and blinded us. We have lost compassion for our environment, that so abundantly provides the most precious goods, which without it, we would be dead in a minute. That is oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, we have no compassion when it comes to deforesting the earth to make paper. Just because the wood lobby would not benefit by using hemp as the primary source of paper 200 years ago. One acre of hemp produces the same amount of paper as 5 acres of trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have concluded that compassion is a notion that should be part of our education. Learning to appreciate the earth that provides for us nutrients for our body and other material for clothing and housing. There is such a disconnect from reality these days that a kid growing up now can recognise over 100 brand logos but not a single plant. Therefore, our newest generations would rightly assume that food comes from McDonalds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being compassionate to our environment and others is something to aspire to become but it doesn’t happen overnight. The more you can disconnect from the material world that is made up around us and start connecting with the physical world, the sooner you can start appreciating that nature’s compassion has no limits towards our destructive behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another concept that we don’t learn in schools is kindness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you killed a spider?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems so tiny and so insignificant but it has a place here. That primarily stems from lack of love and kindness to ourselves. We are harsh and unjust to us. We criticise and judge ourself about our actions and mistakes and we almost never acknowledge our successes. We expect others to do that for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is person left with when he is abusive to himself and seeks approval and praise from others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is almost impossible to be kind to others if you always criticise yourself. However, there are cases that people believe that they deserve to be miserable and being kind to others is more appropriate, as the ones who diverse it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You wouldn’t accept someone being rude to you but you do this to yourself every minute of the day. Take the time to weed out these beliefs that hold you back and stop justifying these behaviours to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindness to ourselves can have astonishing results for the whole world. We affect our environment, with the thoughts we have and the energy we emit.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/compassion-has-no-limit&quot;&gt;Compassion has no limit. Kindness has no enemy.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Morning Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;The Morning Writer&lt;/a&gt; on May 02, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[By Honouring Your Words, you are honoured]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/by-honouring-your-words" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/by-honouring-your-words</id>
  <published>2016-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Morning Writer</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>info@themorningwriter.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The simple premise of staying true to your words is something of a lost art. In the last few centuries, traits like honour and truth have been watered down as more and more of our lives become digital. We spend an awful amount of time existing in a made up universe where nothing is tangible anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of human touch and connection erodes moral traits that have been passed down by previous generations. Without honour we would still be cavemen. Although this could be debated as well. There was something honourable in striving to survive. We are not striving to survive in the same way anymore; are we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we are not being chased by wild animals, there is an invisible digital world that plays out in our head that manifests itself in the real world. There are some many projects going on at once and this creates an inner turmoil. Nothing is visible externally to others. It looks like, as if we could be occupied by nothing. Just staring at a computer screen, agonising to get something done, something not able to account for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mere fact that we set out to accomplish something; anything and we don’t get there, starts to dilute our own being. We can’t keep our word to ourselves anymore. That’s when shame sets in and we start to perceive ourselves as dishonourable people. It doesn’t take much to go down this path. It could be just not having sent that email you promised to someone. The disappointment that overcomes us, it two-fold. We fail to be true to our word for us and then to somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These feelings of unworthiness in the grand scheme of things is minute, but it is enough to take us down a dark path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when taking hold of your brain and affirming to yourself the truth is the turning point. There is no point lying to yourself. That is the last thing you want to do. Accept things as they are and set a new starting point. The past is the past. You can’t change what you did a minute ago, but you can learn and don’t repeat it the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The psychological fallacies that succumb us, are partly to blame but lack of education is the real culprit here. Learning how to interpret what is happening to you, is key for prioritising your life and do what you said you were going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing worst than a lifetime having gone by and realising at the end of your days that you allowed circumstances and things outside of your control to be your excuse for not being true to yourself and honouring your words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Small steps today, make giant leaps in a year from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start today to honour yourself, by reflecting, prioritising and valuing your words and your actions. Don’t follow the path of least resistance with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Think before you speak and don’t speak before you have a sense of the weight of your words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/by-honouring-your-words&quot;&gt;By Honouring Your Words, you are honoured&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Morning Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;The Morning Writer&lt;/a&gt; on May 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life is a chance. Love is infinity. Grace is reality.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/life-is-a-chance" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/life-is-a-chance</id>
  <published>2016-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Morning Writer</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>info@themorningwriter.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Life is a test. An everyday non-stop, relentless test of faith, willpower, endurance and mental strain. This is inevitable and it is part of the package. We all get the same. Like a never ending groundhog day. We wake up either prepared, or not having learnt our lessons, we wake up unprepared to face the same mistakes and walk into the same pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There must be a point in the a point in the day for reflection and evaluation. What did I learn today? What can I use as a guide tomorrow? This is something most of us don’t do and we’re bound to repeat the same mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens a few days in a row; that is we fail to learn from our mistakes, we end up rolling out of bed and into days of anger, bitterness and disappointment. There is no escaping this moment of despair or so we think and feel. There is another version of ourselves in a parallel universe that is happy, fulfilled and jumps out of bed each morning to seize the day. What are they doing differently?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps they say NO more often, as much as to other people, as they do to themselves. Self-discipline is a catalytic component in making strides towards your imagined life. It is the glue that creates tangible, measurable progress that propels you even closer to what is possible. Being able to say no to yourself, when procrastination creeps in, and it does when our self-discipline is watered down by what we see as obstacles, is the golden point we must recognise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Procrastination is a survival mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It kicks in when our brain turns on the fight or flight response and deems it appropriate to postpone what we might perceive life threatening or a threat to our day. The facades of procrastination are countless, as it adjusts itself to our current situation and circumstances. Watching TV or binge watching Netflix when you should be writing that book or buying things you don’t need, to occupy your time and your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a consequence of dreading your days. Yet life is not eternal. We are here for a short time in the grand scheme of things and piss it down the drain. Love is infinity. Love is eternal. Now that is a notion worth adopting into our lives and making it full and long. Love is as fluid and clear as the water and has the ability to cleanse itself like the water does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never learn such things in school. It isn’t in the curriculum. It doesn’t get you a job. What about getting a life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main concern is survival and not living. That’s the schooling system’s product. That’s not reality, it is a delusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grace is another misplaced word in our education. Grace is reality. Observing nature, one will find that from the tiniest flower to the biggest tree, there is grace in their demeanour and how they move with the wind. That reminds me of a verse from a poem about perseverance and change. Good Timber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good timber does not grow with ease:
The stronger wind, the stronger trees;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopt grace in your every day and every activity. It will make things more interesting. When I come to think of it again, we love to be in the company of other people who have grace and love for life.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/life-is-a-chance&quot;&gt;Life is a chance. Love is infinity. Grace is reality.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by The Morning Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;The Morning Writer&lt;/a&gt; on April 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>